<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<anime id="10022" restricted="false">
<type>TV Special</type>
<episodecount>1</episodecount>
<startdate>2013-12-31</startdate>
<enddate>2013-12-31</enddate>
<titles>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="main">Sword Art Online: Extra Edition</title>
<title xml:lang="x-jat" type="short">SAOEE</title>
<title xml:lang="ja" type="official">ソードアート・オンライン Extra Edition</title>
<title xml:lang="fr" type="official">Sword Art Online Extra Edition</title>
</titles>
<relatedanime>
<anime id="10376" type="Sequel">Sword Art Online II</anime>
<anime id="8692" type="Prequel">Sword Art Online</anime>
</relatedanime>
<recommendations total="9">
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="71837">Just a recap.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="231802">As many had mentioned, its mainly a recap of SAO and ALO + some 20 minutes ALO extras with a sprinkle of fan service particular on Leafa and Asuna

It feels like an easy re-watch of SAO and ALO. I do find it abit annoying that it had to stop short an exciting re-capped fight scene just at the climax. 

Watch if you have nothing else to do, or are planning to multitask some phone MMO games while watching anime.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="403846">The recap is nice before S2, but the extra "episode" at the end just flat out sucked.

Only recommended for those who have seen S1 and are going to watch S2. To freshen up the memory :)</recommendation>
<recommendation type="For Fans" uid="371670">Basically a recap with an extra new scene which starts around 1h20min. Watch it since then if you don`t want to waste time. ;)</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="382820">Pretty nice recap with some new stuff at the last 20minutes, i thinks its a great watch and gets you really pumped ab for SAO2</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="139484">Just a recap with some talks among the girls as reflection on their memories...   that 20 mins long new scene, the underwater quest at the end isnt in the light novels, so its just totally random.
Only for those who wanna knoew something about the 1st season of SAO before the 2nd season.</recommendation>
<recommendation type="Recommended" uid="33154">Yes it`s a recap but with an extra story that was not in the light novel that I have read.

Then again this is a prep for those who haven`t seen the first SAO and wish to see SAO II that is going to come out which cover Phantom Bullet and Mother`s Rosario arcs.

So if you want to watch SAO II and don`t want to go back to watch SAO (which I wouldn`t know why you wouldn`t) then at less watch this first.</recommendation>
</recommendations>
<url>http://www.swordart-online.net/extra</url>
<creators>
<name id="704" type="Music">Kajiura Yuki</name>
<name id="8899" type="Chief Animation Direction">Adachi Shingo</name>
<name id="8068" type="Direction">Itou Tomohiko</name>
<name id="28670" type="Original Work">Kawahara Reki</name>
<name id="8899" type="Character Design">Adachi Shingo</name>
<name id="1303" type="Animation Work">A-1 Pictures</name>
</creators>
<description>Kirito and the others decide to go on an underwater quest within the world of ALO to grant Yui her wish to see a whale. As they all prepare for the quest, they face a shocking revelation... Leafa (Suguha) is afraid of water. So, Asuna and the other female members decide to teach Suguha how to swim at a pool in the real world. Meanwhile, Kirito was meeting somebody...
Source: Aniplex</description>
<ratings>
<permanent count="595">4.20</permanent>
<temporary count="601">6.60</temporary>
</ratings>
<picture>147930.jpg</picture>
<categories>
<category id="306" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="400">
<name>Adventure</name>
<description>Adventures are exciting stories, with new experiences or exotic locales. Adventures are designed to provide an action-filled, energetic experience for the viewer. Rather than the predominant emphasis on violence and fighting that is found in pure action anime, however, the viewer of adventures can live vicariously through the travels, conquests, explorations, creation of empires, struggles and situations that confront the main characters, actual historical figures or protagonists. Under the category of adventures, we can include traditional swashbucklers, serialized films, and historical spectacles, searches or expeditions for lost continents, "jungle" and "desert" epics, treasure hunts and quests, disaster films, and heroic journeys or searches for the unknown. Adventure films are often set in an historical period, and may include adapted stories of historical or literary adventure heroes, kings, battles, rebellion, or piracy.</description>
</category>
<category id="369" parentid="282" hentai="false" weight="100">
<name>Breast Fondling</name>
<description>Part of the slapstick comedy in ecchi anime between female characters. E.g. a girl envious of another girl`s bust size may tease the latter via fondling. Usually playful and mischievous, not sexual.

Alas, now the tag can also imply "boob grabbing", where a male character will either accidentally or intentionally touch the breasts of a female. The former is a comedy element, as in "accidental infringement", the latter can be interpreted as a form of harassment.</description>
</category>
<category id="282" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="200">
<name>Ecchi</name>
<description>Ecchi, or etchi (エッチ), is a common Japanese word meaning "indecent", "lewd", "frisky" or "sexy"; its usage can be compared to the English word "naughty". Among western anime fans, the term is used when vague sexual content, such as skimpy clothing or nudity, is prominent. In Japanese, however, it is a catch-all term for all things anyhow sexual in nature, mild or otherwise.</description>
</category>
<category id="252" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="400">
<name>Angst</name>
<description>A feeling of general discomfort and uneasiness is present due to either trivial or more serious reasons, often accompanied by depression.&#13;
&#13;
Warning: may contain copious amounts of brooding and sighing.</description>
</category>
<category id="173" parentid="4" hentai="false" weight="400">
<name>Swordplay</name>
<description>The act or art of using a sword or similar weapon skillfully.</description>
</category>
<category id="8" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="400">
<name>Sci-Fi</name>
<description>Science fiction stories usually focus on how situations could be different in the future when we are more technologically advanced; due to either our own achievements or having met with other civilizations whom we have learned from. </description>
</category>
<category id="266" parentid="15" hentai="false" weight="500">
<name>High Fantasy</name>
<description>Generally a serious and epic story set in an invented world. The world may be more or less based on real world environments or history. Typical fantastical elements are usually dominating, such as elves, dwarves, magicians, invented languages, quests; just to name a few.</description>
</category>
<category id="175" parentid="15" hentai="false" weight="400">
<name>Magic</name>
<description>In a traditional Fantasy anime with medieval setting, the lack of technology is "compensated" by the introduction of the supernatural, i.e. spell-casting, magic wands, and magic circles. &#13;
&#13;
In another setting long-lost technology may be so advanced that it is mistaken for magic (Arthur C. Clarke: "Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic"). See also related tag: science and magic coexist.</description>
</category>
<category id="130" parentid="291" hentai="false" weight="600">
<name>Virtual Reality</name>
<description>A virtual reality is a place where the character interacts with a computer (or some other device)-simulated environment, be it real or imagined. The condition for a virtual reality to exist is the existence of real world for the character. In some cases, a virtual reality where characters can get harmed physically is depicted.</description>
</category>
<category id="462" parentid="15" hentai="false" weight="400">
<name>Fairies</name>
<description>Fairies are small spirits that live in the forest and use their magical dust to do miracles.&#13;
&#13;
Think Tinkerbell, or even Edward from Twilight. :P</description>
</category>
<category id="4" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="300">
<name>Action</name>
<description>Action anime usually involve a fairly straightforward story of good guys versus bad guys, where most disputes are resolved by using physical force. It often contains a lot of shooting, explosions and fighting. </description>
</category>
<category id="198" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="400">
<name>Romance</name>
<description>Romance describes a story that deals with love between two or more characters typically also having an optimistic ending. Romance is also a difficulty encountered when creating a harem.</description>
</category>
<category id="15" parentid="313" hentai="false" weight="600">
<name>Fantasy</name>
<description>Imaginative or fanciful work, especially one dealing with supernatural elements and themes.</description>
</category>
</categories>
<resources>
<resource type="1">
<externalentity>
<identifier>15743</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="2">
<externalentity>
<identifier>20021</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="4">
<externalentity>
<url>http://www.swordart-online.net/extra</url>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="6">
<externalentity>
<identifier>Sword_Art_Online#Anime</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="7">
<externalentity>
<identifier>ソードアート・オンライン#.E3.83.86.E3.83.AC.E3.83.93.E3.82.A2.E3.83.8B.E3.83.A1</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
<resource type="10">
<externalentity>
<identifier>16669</identifier>
</externalentity>
</resource>
</resources>
<tags>
<tag id="4014" approval="4" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2010-03-08">
<name>too many recaps</name>
<count>21</count>
<description>Either to give the audience that missed a few episodes another chance to catch up on the overall "long-winding" story, or simply to save some production costs, this anime repeatedly reuses previously broadcast material (see "fillers").
Since such recap episodes rarely add new material, the viewer will normally not be amused.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="7532" approval="1" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2014-02-17">
<name>better than the real world</name>
<count>2</count>
<description>This type of animation makes you want to escape the real world and actually be part of the anime because the graphic is way better than reality.
Not only due to the better graphics though, but also due to the characters, story line, etc. Simply put, you want to be inside the world of anime!</description>
</tag>
<tag id="7575" approval="2" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2013-10-29">
<name>underwater</name>
<count>4</count>
<description>Underwater is a term describing the realm below the surface of water where the water exists in a natural feature such as an ocean, sea, lake, pond, or river.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4570" approval="3" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-02-21">
<name>beach episode</name>
<count>290</count>
<description>Also known as umi episode. Every anime has to have them, episodes in which the characters for whatever reason end up going to the sea, ocean, random island or the local pond.
Usually used for fanservice purpose as it gives the staff the opportunity to draw the characters in swimsuits and raise the DVD sales.
The cheap version is the pool episode.
Other marginally less used variants of this are the onsen episode and the sentou episode, used when it is too cold for a beach/pool episode.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="7353" approval="1" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2014-02-17">
<name>Yggdrasil</name>
<count>8</count>
<description>This anime contains a system or other-worldly existence based on Norse mythology called Yggdrasil.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="5873" approval="1" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2010-03-08">
<name>barefooted character</name>
<count>38</count>
<description>One of the protagonists never seems to wear any shoes — possibly a martial artist that prefers to stay in close contact with the ground, or a girl from the country now living in the city.
A potential "moe" element for female characters.
Alas, under more dire circumstances this can also be a sign of real poverty.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2365" approval="1" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2010-04-11">
<name>teamwork</name>
<count>49</count>
<description>A cooperative effort by the members of a group or team to achieve a common goal.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="2729" approval="1" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-04-02">
<name>girls with swords</name>
<count>73</count>
<description>Female characters with various swords as their main weapon of choice. Although the size and shape of the blade is often unique and even drastically over-sized, the wielder is almost always free from extra restraint it would be thought to inflict upon them.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4552" approval="1" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2012-10-07">
<name>RPG elements</name>
<count>42</count>
<description>The anime shows elements of a `R`ole `P`laying `G`ame, either as part of a parody or because the anime is actually based on an RPG.
Typical elements: When collecting items, beating opponents, or levelling up a distinct (often childishly sounding) sound cue is played. A HUD (`H`eads `U`p `D`isplay) may also be presenting in combat, showing vital player and "enemy" statistics.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="4571" approval="4" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2009-02-21">
<name>pool episode</name>
<count>169</count>
<description>An episode playing at the pool, mostly in school, sometimes outside of it when the cast does not have a chance for a beach episode.
Usually used for fanservice purpose as it gives the staff the opportunity to draw the characters in swimsuits and raise the DVD sales.
The cheap version of the beach episode.
Other variants are the onsen episode and the sentou episode.</description>
</tag>
<tag id="825" approval="3" spoiler="false" localspoiler="false" globalspoiler="false" update="2014-02-07">
<name>swimsuit</name>
<count>237</count>
<description>A swimsuit is a garment designed to be worn by people engaging in water-based activities or sports or during certain activities under sunlight. Most kinds of swimsuit reveal a large portion of the body surface area. In anime, it is common for at least one episode to feature the characters in swimsuits, usually as an excuse for gratuitous fanservice; swimsuits, and in particular one-piece swimsuits, are a very common fetish in Japan.</description>
</tag>
</tags>
<characters>
<character id="37272" type="main character in" update="2012-07-16">
<rating votes="166">7.32</rating>
<name>Asuna</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>A friend of Kirito and is a sub-leader of the guild Knights of Blood (KoB), a medium-sized guild of about thirty player, also called the strongest guild in Aincrad. Being one of the few many girls that play SAO, and even more so that she`s extremely pretty, she receives many invitations and proposals. She is a skilled player earning the Title "Flash" for her extraordinary sword skill. The KoB has assigned her two bodyguards, one of whom despises Kirito. Her game alias is the same as her Real World name. She later on falls in love with Kirito, eventually leading to them being married.</description>
<picture>83185.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="5" picture="37146.jpg">Tomatsu Haruka</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="37273" type="main character in" update="2012-03-09">
<rating votes="167">6.32</rating>
<name>Kirito</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>The main protagonist of the series. He is the protagonist and is a "solo" player, a player who hasn`t joined a guild and usually works alone. When it is announced that the players of Sword Art Online can no longer logout, he is surprised like everyone else, but unlike everyone else he quickly gets over it and accepts it, to an extent. He mainly uses a one-handed sword and usually wears all black in game, as it adds to stealth. He can also use two blades at once, a unique skill to him and he only uses it in emergencies to avoid attention for being one out of the two people to have unique skills. His game alias is Kirito, which is created by taking the syllables of the first and last Kanji of his real last and first names respectively: (Kirigaya Kazuto). In the real world, he lives with his mother and younger sister in a family of 3.</description>
<picture>83186.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="20249" picture="52461.jpg">Matsuoka Yoshitsugu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="39515" type="appears in" update="2012-09-15">
<rating votes="42">5.43</rating>
<name>Yui</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>94193.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="1443" picture="23192.jpg">Itou Kanae</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="39516" type="appears in" update="2012-10-13">
<rating votes="40">6.25</rating>
<name>Leafa</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>126802.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="590" picture="45927.jpg">Taketatsu Ayana</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="41185" type="appears in" update="2012-05-14">
<rating votes="56">5.43</rating>
<name>Silica</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>87804.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="430" picture="129542.jpg">Hidaka Rina</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="41186" type="appears in" update="2012-04-10">
<rating votes="55">5.48</rating>
<name>Lisbeth</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>85684.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="411" picture="17475.jpg">Takagaki Ayahi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="43410" type="appears in" update="2012-04-10">
<rating votes="13">5.74</rating>
<name>Sachi</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>85683.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="2296" picture="21985.jpg">Hayami Saori</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="43411" type="appears in" update="2012-04-10">
<rating votes="23">5.35</rating>
<name>Egil</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>85681.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="64" picture="16667.jpg">Yasumoto Hiroki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="43412" type="appears in" update="2012-04-10">
<rating votes="19">3.00</rating>
<name>Kayaba Akihiko</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>85680.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="380" picture="38028.jpg">Yamadera Kouichi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="43413" type="appears in" update="2012-04-10">
<rating votes="34">6.39</rating>
<name>Klein</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>85682.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="323" picture="17160.jpg">Hirata Hiroaki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="46770" type="appears in" update="2012-07-08">
<rating votes="1">4.98</rating>
<name>Kayaba Akihiko</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>90677.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="380" picture="38028.jpg">Yamadera Kouichi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="46771" type="main character in" update="2012-10-13">
<rating votes="31">7.10</rating>
<name>Kirigaya Kazuto</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>126810.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="20249" picture="52461.jpg">Matsuoka Yoshitsugu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="46772" type="appears in" update="2012-07-08">
<rating votes="8">3.59</rating>
<name>Kirito</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>90679.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="20249" picture="52461.jpg">Matsuoka Yoshitsugu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="46773" type="appears in" update="2012-07-08">
<rating votes="3">3.76</rating>
<name>Klein</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>90680.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="323" picture="17160.jpg">Hirata Hiroaki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="46906" type="secondary cast in" update="2012-10-13">
<rating votes="47">5.58</rating>
<name>Kirigaya Suguha</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>126809.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="590" picture="45927.jpg">Taketatsu Ayana</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="46907" type="appears in" update="2012-07-15">
<rating votes="3">2.43</rating>
<name>Kibaou</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>90982.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="236" picture="132757.jpg">Seki Tomokazu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="46908" type="appears in" update="2012-07-15">
<rating votes="3">4.03</rating>
<name>Diabel</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>90983.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="73" picture="58662.jpg">Hiyama Nobuyuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="47143" type="appears in" update="2012-07-22">
<rating votes="3">5.19</rating>
<name>Illfang the Kobold Lord</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>91315.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="47349" type="appears in" update="2012-07-28">
<name>Pina</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>91654.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="10410" picture="46169.jpg">Izawa Shiori</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="47538" type="appears in" update="2012-08-04">
<rating votes="1">6.09</rating>
<name>Yolko</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>91963.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="48169" type="appears in" update="2012-08-25">
<rating votes="4">1.61</rating>
<name>Kuradeel</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>92980.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="370" picture="39849.jpg">Yusa Kouji</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="48170" type="appears in" update="2012-08-25">
<name>The Gleam Eyes</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>92981.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="48396" type="appears in" update="2012-10-07">
<rating votes="12">5.45</rating>
<name>Heathcliff</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>93344.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="382" picture="17228.jpg">Ookawa Tooru</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="48920" type="appears in" update="2012-09-15">
<rating votes="1">6.09</rating>
<name>Sasha</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>94195.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="48921" type="appears in" update="2012-09-15">
<name>Mina</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>94194.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="49229" type="appears in" update="2012-09-22">
<name>Sinker</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>94743.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="49230" type="appears in" update="2012-09-22">
<rating votes="1">6.09</rating>
<name>Yulier</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>94742.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="49824" type="appears in" update="2012-10-13">
<rating votes="53">6.33</rating>
<name>Asuna</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>126806.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="5" picture="37146.jpg">Tomatsu Haruka</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="49825" type="appears in" update="2012-10-13">
<rating votes="39">4.16</rating>
<name>Kirito</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>126807.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="20249" picture="52461.jpg">Matsuoka Yoshitsugu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="49826" type="appears in" update="2012-10-13">
<rating votes="26">1.06</rating>
<name>Sugou Nobuyuki</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>126808.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="139" picture="29283.jpg">Koyasu Takehito</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="49827" type="appears in" update="2012-10-13">
<rating votes="28">6.43</rating>
<name>Yui</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>59374.png</picture>
<seiyuu id="1443" picture="23192.jpg">Itou Kanae</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="49857" type="main character in" update="2012-12-22">
<rating votes="29">8.61</rating>
<name>Yuuki Asuna</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>129840.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="5" picture="37146.jpg">Tomatsu Haruka</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="49859" type="appears in" update="2012-10-13">
<name>Yuuki Shouzou</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>126842.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="4494" picture="26772.jpg">Yamaji Kazuhiro</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="49983" type="appears in" update="2012-10-20">
<rating votes="4">1.85</rating>
<name>Recon</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>127064.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="30656" picture="82177.jpg">Murase Ayumu</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="49986" type="appears in" update="2012-10-20">
<rating votes="8">5.04</rating>
<name>Sakuya</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>127067.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="89" picture="148709.jpg">Yahagi Sayuri</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="49987" type="appears in" update="2012-10-20">
<rating votes="8">6.79</rating>
<name>Alicia Luu</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>127068.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="305" picture="37148.jpg">Saitou Chiwa</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="49988" type="appears in" update="2012-10-20">
<rating votes="9">1.02</rating>
<name>Obeiron</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>127069.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="139" picture="29283.jpg">Koyasu Takehito</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="50685" type="appears in" update="2012-11-17">
<rating votes="2">2.90</rating>
<name>Eugene</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>128248.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="178" picture="16985.jpg">Miyake Kenta</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51225" type="appears in" update="2012-12-10">
<rating votes="4">2.72</rating>
<name>Kirigaya Kazuto</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>129277.jpg</picture>
</character>
<character id="51226" type="appears in" update="2012-12-10">
<rating votes="3">6.85</rating>
<name>Kirigaya Suguha</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>129278.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="590" picture="45927.jpg">Taketatsu Ayana</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51578" type="appears in" update="2012-12-22">
<rating votes="20">7.70</rating>
<name>Asuna</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>129830.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="5" picture="37146.jpg">Tomatsu Haruka</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51579" type="secondary cast in" update="2012-12-22">
<rating votes="2">6.18</rating>
<name>Shinozaki Rika</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>129831.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="411" picture="17475.jpg">Takagaki Ayahi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51580" type="secondary cast in" update="2012-12-22">
<rating votes="8">6.86</rating>
<name>Ayano Keiko</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>129832.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="430" picture="129542.jpg">Hidaka Rina</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51590" type="appears in" update="2014-01-02">
<rating votes="2">2.90</rating>
<name>Egil</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Egil`s avatar in Alfheim Online.</description>
<picture>148012.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="64" picture="16667.jpg">Yasumoto Hiroki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51591" type="appears in" update="2014-01-02">
<rating votes="4">8.19</rating>
<name>Silica</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Silica`s avatar in Alfheim Online.</description>
<picture>148014.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="430" picture="129542.jpg">Hidaka Rina</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51592" type="appears in" update="2014-01-02">
<rating votes="4">5.32</rating>
<name>Lisbeth</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Lisbeth`s avatar in Alfheim Online.</description>
<picture>148013.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="411" picture="17475.jpg">Takagaki Ayahi</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="51593" type="appears in" update="2014-01-02">
<rating votes="3">3.88</rating>
<name>Klein</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Klein`s avatar in Alfheim Online.</description>
<picture>148011.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="323" picture="17160.jpg">Hirata Hiroaki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="62759" type="secondary cast in" update="2014-01-02">
<name>Kikuoka Seijirou</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<description>Kikuoka Seijirou is a member of the Ministry of Internal Affairs and Communications, Technology, Second Separated Advanced Network Division, or Virtual Division.
Source: SAO wikia</description>
<picture>147999.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="341" picture="52370.jpg">Morikawa Toshiyuki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="62770" type="appears in" update="2014-01-02">
<rating votes="1">6.09</rating>
<name>Counseling no Sensei</name>
<gender>female</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>148010.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="229" picture="69048.jpg">Itou Miki</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="62771" type="appears in" update="2014-01-02">
<name>Nerakk</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>148015.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3273" picture="53021.jpg">Hazama Michio</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="62772" type="appears in" update="2014-01-02">
<name>Kraken</name>
<gender>unknown</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>148016.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="3273" picture="53021.jpg">Hazama Michio</seiyuu>
</character>
<character id="62773" type="appears in" update="2014-01-02">
<name>Leviathan</name>
<gender>male</gender>
<charactertype id="1">Character</charactertype>
<picture>148017.jpg</picture>
<seiyuu id="416" picture="23206.jpg">Saka Osamu</seiyuu>
</character>
</characters>
<episodes>
<episode id="154807" update="2014-01-01">
<epno type="1">1</epno>
<length>100</length>
<airdate>2013-12-31</airdate>
<rating votes="1">5.78</rating>
<title xml:lang="en">TV Special</title>
</episode>
</episodes>
</anime>
